<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home page of Debamitro Chakraborti</title>
    <link>https://debamitro.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home page of Debamitro Chakraborti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 12:09:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://debamitro.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Same Mistake for a Decade</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/making-the-same-mistake-for-a-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 12:09:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/making-the-same-mistake-for-a-decade/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw I had made the same mistake twice in a month. It is a rather harmless-looking mistake in C.
I first saw it in 2006, barely a year after I started working as a software engineer. Someone was having a crash only with a 64-bit build. Two people were looking into it and I somehow got involved. A function was returning a pointer to a structure and dereferencing this pointer was causing a crash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Got Into Clojure</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/how-i-got-into-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 20:27:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/how-i-got-into-clojure/</guid>
      <description>I had read wonderful things about Clojure many years ago in a blog post series. At that time it seemed very different from the type of programming I used to do at my day job. I had no idea that it could be used for creating any of the software programs I used.
StrangeLoop and Alda I attended StrangeLoop for the first time in 2017 - and my mind was blown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An in-home Social Network</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/an-in-home-social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 21:48:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/an-in-home-social-network/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking about creating social networks for specific purposes, when one day I figured out it would be good to have a social network restricted to my home. I got this idea looking at my son and thinking what he would do on Facebook a few years from now. I have nothing against Facebook or any social network - I think they are all fabulous. I just think that an internet-based social network is like the world outside your home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC for two days</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-for-two-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 17:27:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-for-two-days/</guid>
      <description>After a lot of thought and planning I came down to RC for two days, alongwith a fellow Recurser from Boston.
Recap In 2018 I did a mini batch at RC and simply loved it! I did not like staying away from my nine-month-old son for five days, though. So I decided against doing another batch for a year or two.
NGW 2019 I attended Never Graduate Week with my wife (a senior Recurser) and son and loved the experience!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 5</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 08:37:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day5/</guid>
      <description>(My notes from the final day of RC Mini 5 batch)
8:39 am Today is the last day of my batch. I plan to spend the day exploring some codebases. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time writing code today. I might write some fun code, though.
11:08 am I tried to read the alda codebase to find out where they specify frequencies of notes. Alda was my first exposure to Clojure, and I had wanted to experiment with the frequencies of the notes to see if I could play accurate Indian classical music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 09:37:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day4/</guid>
      <description>(My notes from the fourth day of RC Mini 5 batch)
9:47 am I started a bit late today, and got delayed by having to skip one subway train because it was soooo crowded. I am beginning to feel that although I have completed most of my work in Clojure, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done functional programming yet. I have not used any global state, and accomplished everything by calling a series of functions from other functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 08:15:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day3/</guid>
      <description>(My notes from the third day of RC Mini 5 batch)
8:19 am I have been reading The Joy of Clojure everyday. I need to find ways to improve my Clojure code. So far I have succeeded in avoiding loops by using recursion. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to operate on lists as a whole yet, and neither have I been able to use things like the continuation-passing-style. I can&amp;rsquo;t use something &amp;lsquo;foo&amp;rsquo; unless the code stares at me in the face and says &amp;ldquo;this is the place to try out foo&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 07:56:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day2/</guid>
      <description>(My notes from the second day of RC Mini 5 batch)
7:58 am I have been up since 6:30am. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get started with today at RC. I have been thinking about how to process a variable number of characters from a string in Clojure. I keep getting stuck because I still have the C++ while loop code in my head!
10:10 am I was the first person in RC today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 09:13:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day1/</guid>
      <description>9:15 am I woke up at my usual time of somewhere-between-6:30-and-7:00. Thanks to my son I don&amp;rsquo;t need alarms! I headed out after an hour in search of Dr Strange&amp;rsquo;s Sanctum Sanctorum. I went to 177A Bleecker St - there was no house with that address. I was helped by an &amp;#9730; in my search. I took a photo of the shop at 177. Now I am about to head to RC after a small breakfast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Mini 5 - Day 0</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 13:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini5-day0/</guid>
      <description>10:57 am I am going to the Recurse Center. Can&amp;rsquo;t believe it yet. Right now I am sitting in the bus and heading towards Boston&amp;rsquo;s South Station. Two years ago my wife did a full batch at RC and that changed her life. It changed my life as well - I became convinced that RC was a &amp;ldquo;must-do&amp;rdquo;. It would not have been possible for me to do a full batch unless I quit my job, so my only hope was a half batch which lasts six weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 14:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an amateur musician, professional programmer, as well as a husband and a father.
aami ekajan bAngAlI progrAmAr 
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 14:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Does every programmer need to have projects on the side? That&amp;rsquo;s what the world wants to believe.
Here are some very tiny and simple things I have tried.
 TicTacToe using reagent Generating MIDI files using C++11  Here are some not-so-tiny things I have done.
 Bangla transliterator from Roman letters to Unicode ClojureScript version of the above  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>