<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mini 6 2020 on Home page of Debamitro Chakraborti</title>
    <link>https://debamitro.github.io/tags/mini-6-2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mini 6 2020 on Home page of Debamitro Chakraborti</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 12:50:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://debamitro.github.io/tags/mini-6-2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rc Mini 6 2020 Day4 and 5</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day4-and-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 12:50:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day4-and-5/</guid>
      <description>Today is the last day of my batch - that&amp;rsquo;s how fast a Mini batch flies by. Let me recap what happened in the last two days&#xA;Interaction with Recursers I had another great coffee chat where we talked about things like the birdsong recognition contest at Kaggle and how remote participation in RC can be more fun. I also got good questions about security in my homesocial project, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought of before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rc Mini 6 2020 Day2 and 3</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day2-and-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 17:45:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day2-and-3/</guid>
      <description>So now I am at the end of day 3 of this batch - which means more than half is over! A lot has happened that I want to write about, although I have made very little progress on the side projects I planned to work on. Like the previous post, I am organizing this one by theme.&#xA;Interaction with Recursers This is going really well - again, by my own standards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rc Mini 6 2020 Day 1</title>
      <link>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 12:38:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://debamitro.github.io/blog/rc-mini6-day1/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the first day of my second mini batch at the Recurse Center. This time I am attending a remote batch, which in itself is a new experience. I had the time to think and plan my time for this batch, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have arrange transport or accommodation. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much of the plan I am following, but I guess I am not too much off track.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
